National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers 5584
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Division of Negro Economics. Files. (Box 24)
  - E - with G.H. Edmunds, United Mine Workers offering his services as Negro Labor Advisor., 1918 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - F - with Governor of Florida, re discontinuance of the Bureau of Home Economics for Negroes in his state; racial literature circulating in Florida; formation and plans of Farm Service Division, United States Employment Service, to keep Negroes from leavin, 1918-1921 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - G - letters of recommendation and routine., 1918 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - H - letters of recommendation and applications for positions; with Charles E. Hall, Supervisor, Negro Economics, Ohio re housing facilities for Negroes, statistical work on Negro wage-earners; literary with Frank Hallin, Editor of "Method;" with Mrs. Joh, 1918-1921 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Haynes, George E. - letters of recommendation and support, release announcing his appointment, 7 page study and report by Haynes re model village in North Carolina and routine., 1918-1921 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - I - Inter-racial Council re immigration and routine., 1918-1925 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - J - with Mary E. Jackson, Secretary, Bureau of the Young Women's Christian Associations, re colored women in industry; with Paul B. Johnson, Captain, Medical Corps re assisting colored soldiers with finding employment after discharge and routine., 1918-1921 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Jackson, Giles B. - President, National Civic Improvement Association re conference with Samuel Gompers, President, AFL, concerning plans for the mobilization of Negro farm labor; ideas on the creation of a Bureau of Negro Labor; congested railroad situat, 1917-1919 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Jennifer, William - President, "The Detroit Compass," re literary (1920) and special agent, United States Employment Service., 1919-1921 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Jones, Eugene K. - Executive Secretary of National League on Urban Conditions Among Negroes, and later National Urban League, 2 page statement re race riots in Washington and Chicago distributed by National Urban League, and routine., 1918-1921 (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Division of Negro Economics. Files. (Box 25)
  - K - letters of recommendation from State of Kansas, Governor Arthur Capper and other routine., 1918-1921 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - L - with Morris Lewis, Commissioner of Conciliation, Department, re unemployment for Blacks in Chicago area; legislative bill and memo re creating Negro Industrial Commission (1924) and routine., 1919-1928 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Lynching Petition - petition with several signatures, appealing to William Baker, Secretary of Labor, to stop allowing the lynching of Blacks., 1918 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    March 5, 1918
  - Land Settlement - correspondence with various realty companies re available farm lands for Black settlements (including some advertising literature)., 1920 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - M - routine., 1918-1926 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Migration - re problems of Blacks migrating to the north and thereby depleting the labor supply in the south and plans to try and control it., 1917- 1923 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    6a - Minneapolis Strike - 1917 - re Great Northern importing Negroes to replace white labor.
  - N - Correspondence with NAACP re colored representation on the Advisory Council; re survey of colored workers in New York City; model constitution for local Negro Workers Advisory Committee; Newport News, Virginia, re housing conditions and supply and dem, 1918-1921 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - New Jersey - routine, 1918 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - O-P - routine, 1918 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Q - routine, 1918 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - R - Republican National Committee, Division of Colored Women re their recommendations to the President for positions (for Blacks) in the federal government (1925); A. Phillip Randolph re Pullman Company; National Urban League, Ira Reid re survey of numbe, 1918-1933 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - S - routine., 1917-1932 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - T - letters of recommendation and routine., 1918-1919 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - U - United States Employment Service, "Clearance Bulletin" for week ending August 23, 1919 and routine., 1919-1928 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - V - routine, 1918-1919 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - W - routine., 1918-1926 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous memos, correspondence, etc., 1919-1925 (Box 25, Folder 17)
- U.S. Housing Administration. Files. (Box 26)
  - General File, 1919 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    includes memos from Division of Negro Economics to Director of United States Bureau of Housing and Transportation re housing conditions and Negro home registrations.
  - Bixby, Charles R. -, 1919 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    field agent for United States Homes Registration Committee, correspondence re setting up colored registries in the Central West.
  - Bull, A. H. and Company -, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    correspondence with United States Housing Corporation re application for construction of housing for Negroes in Elizabeth, New Jersey.
  - Commission on Living Conditions of War Workers -, 1918-1919 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    correspondence, reports, surveys and inter- office memos re the centralizing and coordinating all public and private efforts for providing industrial workers in war industries with proper living conditions and recreational opportunities.
  - Edwards, Ray G. -, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Field agent, includes daily report forms giving summary of day's work, persons and places visited and correspondence arranging for separate reports for Negro and white registries.
  - Ford, James -, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Manage, Homes Registration and Information Service, correspondence re organizing Negro registries for various cities, bad housing conditions in Northern industrial centers.
  - Hege, Edwin S. - Manager, Washington Homes Division, United States Housing Corporation -, 1918-1919 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    correspondence and report forms re types of housing accommodations available in various areas; 13 page mimeo "Hearings before Committee on Public Buildings and Grounds. A Bill to Establish a Home or Homes for Aged and Infirm Colored People and Working Girls.. April 10, 1918," and miscellaneous.
  - McCracken, Fred -, 1918-1919 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Field agent, correspondence and daily reports re summary of day's work and persons and places visited.
  - Negro Registries -, 1918-1919 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    correspondence re the establishment of room registration offices for dealing with colored people in cities; need for room registries for colored women.
  - Parker, Carl R. -, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    Miscellaneous correspondence and reports re housing in Newport News - Briarfield, Virginia; school needs in Norfolk, Portsmouth, Newport News, Truxton, and Craddock, Virginia.
  - United States Department of Labor -, 1918-1922 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    file re Negro housing, Negro population and joint resolution for relief of citizens of Truxton, Virginia re its housing corporation.
  - Akron, Ohio -, 1919 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    Field agent's detailed report re critical rooming and housing situation and problems with getting recommendations approved.
  - Alabama - Nitrate Plants and Towns -, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    correspondence re providing housing for workers
  - Bridgeport, Connecticut -, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    re Bridgeport Housing Project problems with Portuguese Negro laborers.
  - Buffalo, New York -, 1917 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    Field agent's report to Chamber of Commerce re building more housing for the increased population of that area.
  - Chicago, Illinois -, 1919 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    correspondence re improving housing conditions for Negroes in Chicago; meetings with Rental Division of the Chicago Real Estate Board; and miscellaneous.
  - Cleveland, Ohio -, 1918-1919 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    field agent's summary of official visit to Cleveland; resolutions re rent profiteering; minutes; complaints re housing costs.
  - Columbus, Ohio -, 1917 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    correspondence re solutions for Columbus Negro housing problems.
  - Detroit, Michigan -, 1917 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    letter re Negroes forcing Italians out of certain sections of the city.
  - Minneapolis, Minnesota -, 1919 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    re critical housing situation.
  - Newport News, Virginia -, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    re values of various properties, reports on housing projects, estimates of costs for projects, statistical information.
  - Nitro, West Virginia - (Box 26, Folder 22)
    report re boarding conditions at plant in Nitro. No date.
- U.S. Housing Administration. Files. (Box 27)
  - Norfolk, Virginia -, 1918-1919 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    re housing project plans and reports for Norfolk and immediate vicinity; estimates of housing sites; living conditions of war workers; architects reports.
  - Norfolk, Virginia -, 1918-1919 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Omaha, Nebraska -, 1919 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    field agent's reports of official visit to Omaha re housing conditions.
  - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania -, 1919 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    correspondence with R.R. Wright, President of the Colored Protective Association re not wanting a white person on commission of living conditions for Negroes in Philadelphia.
  - Richmond, Virginia -, 1917 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    re housing conditions for Negroes.
  - Saint Paul, Minnesota -, 1919 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    report re official visit to Saint Paul concerning housing conditions.
  - Truxton, Virginia -, 1919-1920 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    correspondence, reports, budgets re the Truxton Project; includes information on construction of development, census forms, Truxton employees.
  - Truxton, Virginia, 1919-1920 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Truxton, Virginia, 1919-1920 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Truxton, Virginia -, 1919-1920 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Truxton, Virginia -, 1919-1920 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Washington, DC -, 1918-1919 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    correspondence, reports re housing.
  - Youngstown, Ohio -, 1919 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    re housing conditions
- U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. Survey Files. (Box 28)
  - "Daily Record of Family Expenses", 1918 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    Includes information on Black families re wages, occupation, number of meals at home, and daily record of expenditures.
  - "Cost of Living in the Year Ending July 31, 1918" -, 1917-1918 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    Includes information on white households re annual expenses for food, clothing, housing, utilities, furnishings. Gives description of housing.
  - "Cost of Living in the Year Ending July 31, 1918", 1917-1918 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    Includes information on Black households re annual expenses for food, clothing, housing, utilities, furnishings. Gives description of housing.
  - "Record of Food Consumption for One Work" -, 1936 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    Includes record of food brought into the home for a one-week period. Also includes data on income, rent, occupation and inventory of food on hand of Black households.
  - "Family Disbursements of Wage Earners and Salaried Workers" -, 1936 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    Includes data on occupation, income, and expenditures for housing, clothing, transportation, medical care, education of Black households.
- U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. Survey Files. Miscellaneous. (Box 29)
  - "Family Disbursements of Wage Earners and Salaried Workers" -, 1936 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    Includes data on occupation, income, and expenditure for housing, clothing, transportation, medical care, education of white households.
  - "Family Disbursements of Wage Earners and Salaried Workers" -, 1936 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    Includes data on occupation, income and expenditures for housing, clothing, transportation, medical care, education of white households. Additional data given re housing description, assets and liabilities.
  - National Federation of Colored Farmers, James P. Davis, President., 1930-1931 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence re complaints about Red Cross relief; reports; Hearing transcript, accusing Red Cross of refusing aid to a farmer in Mississippi; clippings.
  - "Negro Education, General Survey, Methods and Scope of the Study, Summary of Educational Facilities." United States Department of the Interior, Bureau of Education. Reprint., 1916 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous index cards (Box 29, Folder 5)